Okay. Uh so when we were planning this
retreat,
uh Tim and I and we were thinking about
what classes to
do and u it's bad
luck in Buddhism not to finish a
teaching. Okay. So like the the last lam
we took 12 years but we finished it and
it we should give ourselves a hand.
[Music]
[Applause]
And there's another uh important
teaching uh it's called dang
shang which mean say dangin
shang
dangin means the tendency to think the
pen is coming from the pen.
grasping to a pen that was made in a
factory and not from you. You see what I
mean? When you hold when you believe
that the pen was made in a factory, you
have this mental illness called dangin
and everybody has it. Okay? Even when
you're teaching the pen, you have
it. Okay? That's funny. Uh but it's very
very old and it's it's inside of you.
Shang means
uh hassle between two people
like in America we have a special thing
you sometimes you can see it if you
visit it's called road
rage and uh drivers hit each other by
accident or something and they both get
really angry and they jump out of their
car and they
start my friend said he got road rage he
he hit somebody in rimrock not Stanley.
And uh he got out of his car and he's
gonna yell at the guy and the guy shows
a gun and he and he goes, "Hey, that was
cool." And so that kind of
uh meeting somebody
uh is called Shangdub. In Tibetan, it's
called Shangdub. It means a like a fight
fight meeting something like that. So in
this book, it's a long book of poetry.
It's called the fight between the good
part of your mind and the bad part of
your mind. And it's a bitter fight. It's
like a road rage fight. Okay. And uh my
teacher introduced it to me many years
ago
probably 354 years ago and uh he taught
it to us. It's very long and he could
not finish. He died before he could
finish and uh it's kind of bad luck to
to not finish. So I thought I would like
to teach it and I would like to finish
the translation and then I feel like I
finished it. You know it's amazing book.
It's a fight in your own mind. It's like
your own mind is split into two and the
good side and the bad side. You know,
like devil and the angel are are
fighting with each other, you know, and
it's an
amazing
conversation and it's a conversation
that we have all the time, you know,
like, oh, you know, this guy really did
hurt me. And then you said, no, it's the
remember the pen. You said, yeah, I know
about the pen thing, but this guy's
different. No, we all say that every
day. We all say it a hundred times every
day. I do it every day. You know, I sit
in my
outhouse freezing
bottom. What's the crulest thing you can
do to a
mama? Put them in Kyoto. All the toilets
are
warm. They have electricity in the sea.
It's like I feel like I'm in paradise.
Then I come back to Diamond Mountain and
my outhouse and
I actually stand up and I say I don't
know if I can sit down. Then I sit down.
I said okay. So anyway even then I'm
arguing in my own mind you know my own
mind is fighting with my own mind and
it's a beautiful beautiful uh book. So
we started it what year Tim? Do you
remember? I don't know. We started it 14
years ago and we're still working on it.
Okay? And I I can I don't have much time
to teach it but I refuse to give up.
Okay? So I'm just stubborn. All
right? And if you are following Diamond
Way, if you're a Diamond Way person,
okay,
maybe the Buddha sent this book to you
this time. Maybe you can't
say yes for sure and you can't say no
for sure. It's
possible that your diamond way path is
is with this book also. Maybe this book
is supposed to help you uh in your
diamond way. And I take it that way. I
I'm not finished with it. It's going to
take another three, four years probably.
and I want to finish it and that's never
been translated correctly and I I would
like
to have it in the world. I would like
people be able to use it. Uh and for me
when I teach it I can understand it
better you know by teaching it by
explaining anything to someone else
which you will learn as teachers. You
guys as
teachers when you want to teach well
then you know try it out on your sister
or your son. How old is
he? 19. Oh my gosh. Uh so he's going to
be a DCI teacher next year.
Yeah. Uh so anyway
uh you know I think it's I think Buddha
sent you this book and you're supposed
to finish it with me. Okay. So I'm
making it part of the Diamond Way
course. Uh it's mainly an argument about
the meaning of emptiness and it's a
unique book because it's funny and it
was written to be funny. Okay. So I
expect you to laugh sometimes. Just
laugh even if you don't understand it.
Just say haha, you know, and uh okay,
it's funny and it's very very true.
Okay, it's a self-criticism, you know.
It's here's what half of grandpa's mind
thinks when just before I sit down in
that special seat. Okay, here's here's
who he blames for the weather. You know
who made it so cold in the morning? Why
don't they make it warm in the m morning
when you do your big
stuff and then it's colder later in the
day? It doesn't make sense, right? No, I
mean,
so you complain in your own mind and and
that's that's called the the devil. In
this case, the bad guy is talking in
your mind. Okay. Now, uh Tim and I
worked very hard on this text.
because you've heard about the idea of
the five
houses and what's happening with
ACI is that uh we've it's I think it's
one of the oldest organizations we have.
It started I think in 19 93 or something
like that. Uh so it's 32 years now.
Okay.
And it grew and it grew and it grew and
YSI came out of it and DCI came out of
it. SEIN came out of it. All the other
SSD, DL, BBB, they all came out of ACI
has been almost 40 years, you know, and
it got too big in a way. It's too big,
you know. you if you take the 18
courses foundation courses it's supposed
to take six to seven years then if you
take the diamond ray courses it's
supposed to take six or seven years
that's 14 years then you're supposed to
do all the meditation stuff that's what
another five years that's 19 years then
you're supposed to do a threeear retreat
someday does it it gets to be like you
don't have enough time to finish ACI
before you die. Uh it's too much. It's
just got to be too much. So what we
thought was what's happening is we would
like you all to be teachers. We really
want you to be teachers. If you're so
stubborn that you come to cook yourself
in the desert in these classes, then
probably you can be a teacher because to
be a teacher is very similar to cooking
yourself at Diamond Mountain. uh it's a
lot of trouble and we thought that the
people who come especially to Diamond
Way you're going to be great teachers
and and that's my dream you know that's
been my dream uh that's what I've been
working on all these years so I what we
thought
was it's so many things to learn you
know you can't study for 40 years and
then be a teacher because you don't have
any hair left after that right done you
and me. So my our idea is you can
specialize. It's like when you go to
university, you don't try to get
a BA in science and then do a a BA in
English and then do a BA in literature
and then do you can't you don't try to
do six BAS at Colombia except you're
some special people. So,
uh, our idea is you could start
specializing, you know, and you're
welcome to come to all the classes. You
don't have to stop coming to any
classes, but maybe you could look inside
your
heart and and there's five choices
basically, okay? There's five
specialties. You can get your BA or your
PhD and then start teaching in one of
five houses. So it's like fraternity
house or at Princeton you had to join a
house you know and then you're very
loyal to your house and and you get
support and you get friends and you
study together and and you you graduate
together in your own house. So we wanted
to make five houses and the choices are
what's the first one? This is by the way
the first rule as a teacher is when you
can't remember something ask the
audience can you remember the first one
classics yeah you can't go the
traditional ACI way you can study all
the classics you can learn the six
courses learn them well then learn the
sorry 18 plus 18 36 courses you can
learn the technical it's basically gish
it's basically a course. If you passed
the first 18 foundation courses of ACI,
uh you have covered the important stuff
of the Gishi course. Okay? By the way,
they don't sit there for 12 hours every
day. They constantly take breaks. In
fact, you never know if there's going to
be a class. Uh they they come you go to
class and it's empty and they say, "Oh,
we didn't have a class today." You're
like, "You didn't tell me that." They
said, "We don't tell people." And uh
they don't study like at a western
university. They It's very crazy. The
system is very crazy. So anyway,
uh you're going to finish the
philosophical, you know, some people
like that word or some people are nerds
and they want to study the philosophy.
I'm like that. I enjoy the philosophy
and I like to talk about it like I learn
things that way. If I ever reach
Buddhahood, it will be philosopher path.
You see what I
mean? Then some people
prefer samadei house which is uh
meditation. Some people just really into
meditation. You say study this book
here. Here's another book. the the last
35 books were not enough and you read
this one and they're like can can't I
just meditate once in a while you know I
I don't want to read books all day and
some people prefer meditation and some
people go deep into it and they enjoy it
and uh and they their dream is to be a
meditation teacher not to be a Tibetan
teacher you see what I mean and that's
fine and we should have a degree like
that we should have a house like that.
You should have the privilege and the
pleasure of joining meditation house. We
call it samadei house. Okay. And
probably you have to look like that when
you
graduate. By the way, great
meditators, really great meditators are
low low, what do you call it? Low
profile. They don't show off. John Brady
is probably the best meditator I know.
And uh he doesn't he doesn't look like
that. The beard's a little different,
but uh no, I mean
uh you know, it's a quiet thing and and
you don't look like something. You could
look like a businesswoman. You could be
a import
export corporate owner in Vietnam, for
example, be a great meditator. Nobody
knows, right? So that's it's up to you,
okay? If you if you're more
attracted to meditation and you when you
see your future, when you close your
eyes and dream about the future, you're
teaching meditation to a group of
people, then you're welcome to join
uh samadei house. doesn't mean you can't
listen to philosophy
classes but it means you specialize
uh you know when
someone when I decide what I am
I it's what I tell people on the
airplane so you sit down to next to
somebody you don't know them and they
say what do you do and if you're the
person who's going to say I'm a
meditation teacher then you should join
Sumati house okay if you're They want to
say, "I want to be a gish." Got it. And
they're saying,
"Well, oh, you're
in." Yeah. Okay. Uh, classics house is
okay. Third house,
what do they call? Mountain house.
Mountain house.
Uh look, I'm really attracted to
retreat, you know, and there's some
people
uh who just would would they they're
hungry to do more retreats. You say,
"Look, I got a new book for you and I'm
going to teach you a new meditation."
And they say, "Oh, I'm sorry. I'm busy."
You say, "What? I'm sitting in my
cabin. You know, I can't read a book. I
can't. You know, they they're like their
thing is they want to be up on a
mountain by
themselves, you know, in deep retreat.
They want people to see them every six
years or so, like like Llama Belma.
Yeah. So anyway, uh if you're that kind
of person who whose dreams of being one
of these great people who who stays in
retreat for a lot, you know, uh then you
could join this house, okay, mountain
house.
I'm not sure the percentage of people
like I I don't know which house is going
to be more popular, but I I do
believe if you can get about five people
in a house to start as the beginning,
it's enough. I don't care. I don't care
if there's a hundred people in the
scripture classics house and there's
only two people in the retreat house. I
don't care. You know it. I want you to
be where you want to be. Okay. So, uh
then what's the fourth one?
Yeah. Stairway house.
Yeah. Lim. Okay. Everyone's going to
call Lim anyway.
Uh yeah, it's easier.
So, as you saw the last 12 years, this
is a huge topic. You know, we covered
one lom
rim and I have
like John's database has a few hundred
lom rims. You can go many many you can
spend the rest of your life in the l
rooms and there's many many
beautiful like the one we just finished
is 12 years. If we did L room tempo it's
12 years. It'd be 24 years just to do
two of them and you can become a master
of London and it's very sweet and maybe
that's what you like. Okay. Then
everybody wants to be in the fifth house
which is diamond house. Is it diamond
way house?
Uh because everybody wants to be in
diamond house. We're not going to allow
you to be in diamond house because then
you'll ignore the other four houses. So,
what we have a plan, me and Uncle
Tim, is uh join one of the four houses.
You you don't have to decide today. You
don't have to cut your blood and sign
the contract. Uh just think about it.
Which one are you more attracted to?
I'll tell you something very profound.
my teacher's advice to me of all the
five gishi topics he said is there one
that you really hate and I said yes and
he said what and I said it's course 13
why do you think unlucky number uh I
said logic I hate logic either and he's
like okay you're going to master that
that's his advice was join the house you
don't like because that's the one that
you are not so good at and when you
balance your life when you master
something you're not interested in
uh then you become a master of both you
see what I mean you're already a good
meditator so okay learn to do retreat or
or learn to do philosophy or something
like that I mean there's that option
okay I'm not forcing you if you always
dreamed of sitting in a cabin and
avoiding other
people, you're welcome to join uh what's
it called? Retreat. Mountain House.
Yeah. Okay. Whatever you like. You're
free. Okay. You're very free. All right.
You But what we ask is this week,
uh we're even going to ask you to kind
of pretend you're in one of the houses.
Okay? Just see how it
feels. I told you my wife's story,
right, that you will never repeat to
her.
I took her to buy jeans in Cottonwood at
the cowboy store where they don't have a
seat for the husband to wait. You have
to stand. And she tried on 42 pairs of
jeans. How many did she buy?
None. Okay. So, what it means is try on
different
houses. See how it fits.
You're not forced to take one or the
other. Okay. You can say that doesn't
fit me so good. I like to What's the
greatest thing I ever did on a tour?
Stanley knows. And I'm
not I I just I I was brave and I bought
her a pair of jeans and they
fit. Okay. I mean, if if you write my
life story after I
die, it should start with he bought his
wife jeans and they fit. Okay.
Okay. So, houses like that. Okay. In
Harry
Potter,
Cury, how do they decide which house
you're in? Slytherin and all that. How
they
decide? Yeah. What's it called? The
what's the hat called?
Oh, the sorting hat. Yeah, we couldn't
get a sorting
hat. In Harry Potter, you put a hat on
and the hat talks, right? And it says
Kiri should be in meditation house. Uh,
so anyway, we don't got this hat. So,
you're going to have to decide for
yourself. Okay.
Where would Harry Potter go if he could
decide by himself?
[Music]
Which house for Harry Potter? Slytherin.
As a bodhis safa, he go to where he
doesn't like the people. Okay.
Uh so
anyway, now the game this week is uh
you're going to buy I don't know
whenever Tim says you're going to choose
a house that you might like to be in
which means what would you like to be a
teacher
of and you know what what would you like
to teach other people mainly and uh and
then you're going to focus on that and
we'll help you focus on your whatever
you choose to be a PhD of we will help
you focus on that and we will design
special courses for you and it doesn't
mean other people can't come but it's
mainly for the house okay so we'll
design specialized courses to make you a
great teacher of your own house okay and
and then if you fulfill certain
requirements in your house you're
allowed to also join diamond house you
see what I mean so your house of The
four is a path to the fifth house
because everybody wants to go to the
fifth house and they're all going to go
around the four houses. So we're asking
you to choose one of the four and then
you go to diamond house from there.
Okay? So kind of diamond house is the
super house for the people in the four
houses who do really well. Okay? And
then you become a teacher in one of
those five things. So think about what
you would like to be a teacher of.
Visualize yourself. Picture yourself as
a teacher. That's that's Diamond Way.
One of the most important Diamond Way
teachings is to imagine yourself what
you're going to be like when you're a
Buddha. Okay, that's one of the most
important Diamond Way meditations is,
you know, what do you want to look like?
Me and John are going to have full hair
like a like a lion. Yeah. and my tummy
is going to go down. No. And you're
gonna, you know, so one of the diamond
way exercises is to visualize yourself
as how you want to be. Okay? And
sometimes you can do that. We'll talk
about it. Okay? Now, the fun we're going
to have with I call the angel devil
book. Okay? The angel devil book. Uh the
fun we're going to have is
um you're going to help me make a flow
doc for this book. Okay, flow doc
means it's a file that I use. I take the
book like the last class we had. I have
Gibson's book in my computer and I uh
cut open a space and I put a picture
there and I teach from the pictures like
I did last class. I teach from the
pictures. So what I did for angel devil
is I don't have
pictures.
Why you're going to do the pictures?
Okay. And each house is going to do
pictures for teaching that part of the
book your way. Okay. So, I'm going to
teach you today some of the next verses
of Angel Devil. It happens to be the
devil being a
[Music]
real okay bad guy. and he's being
very he's being very
disrespectful, which is what he does.
And
uh then I would like each
house you're and Tim's going to lead you
through it, but you're going to sit
together and you're going to design the
itms. You're going to design the the
images to teach it. Then we're going to
have some special classes. They'll be
cut into four parts. Each house will get
up. Here's our picture for the first
verse. Okay, this is how we will teach
the first verse from our house, which is
the best house,
right? You got to be loyal to your
house, right? We got a Harry Potter
expert here. He went through all the
books in like three days or so. He even
reads while he's walking around. There's
called rattlesnakes here. You can't do
that. Okay.
So, you're gonna make it in and
uh nowadays, so I used to have a a a
contract with a photo agency and I
bought photos from them and uh for many
many years and
uh you search online, you know, you say
I want a photo of a irritated lady and
it shows you a pig or something like
it's kind of a stupid AI, but it got
better and better and better. Okay? And
uh now you can design a an image. You
you it's called a prompt and you you
write a sentence. You say, "A lady
spilled her spaghetti on the guy's head
and he's meditating and you write that
and then the the AI makes the picture
and it sometimes they even put five
fingers." Okay. No, but I I really like
it and I use it a lot. Okay. And
probably in your future you'll use video
from your AI or something. But anyway,
in my age it's pretty cool and uh so
you're going to use
AI, you're gonna make a image and it's
great teaching tool. Okay. It keeps the
audience interested. It's what do you
call
entertaining and uh you show a picture
and
then it's great for quizzing your
students you know what's this picture
you know what's this mean you know so
the picture should have a power it
should have a some kind of powerful
picture that tells a story okay and then
it's much easier to remember philosophy
from a picture okay so we're going to
tell a story with pictures. So, I did
not choose the pictures this time. I
want four
pictures for each major teaching I'm
going to give you. And I want to see
what your houses can do. Okay? And then
me and Tim, I don't know, we'll decide
who's the best and you get a gold hat or
something. I don't know. No, that's too
American. Uh, but anyway, we'll have fun
with it. Okay. All right. There was a
famous guy from Mexico who has a news
show. We did this long ago. Do you
remember? We had a contest for
its here. How many 10 years ago or
something? And he he did the best one.
He got he won the award, you know, and
it was amazing. It was really cool. I
think he used up everything on that
day. No, I'm kidding. But uh by the way,
he just got back from Kyoto teaching and
we should give a applause
for him and
[Music]
[Applause]
Adam, they did a very nice uh course in
Kyoto and thanks to Japanese friends
that babysat them because they're kind
of wild. Uh but uh he and Adam Amrad
gave a great
class and they got a grant from Tim and
Nick to go there and give their course
and it was very fun for them.
Accidentally the plane stopped in Hawaii
on the
way and Juan went to
Aahu and the Northshore. Okay. And I
just to teach you Hawai I lived there
for six months and surfed there. But um
which of those two beaches do you go
like
this? Aahu or Northshore?
Both of
them in Aahu is the
bikinis. In Northshore is the
surf. Okay. Right. Juan. So I don't know
which beach you were at.
Uh but uh anyway, if you want to try
something like that, you can apply for a
grant from talk to Tim or Nick. Okay.
And they went to Kyoto and they had a
really good time and they helped a lot
of people. They had a great course and
it it went really well and anybody can
do that. Okay. It's called
Gbox. I'll talk about that someday.
Okay. Uh so here we go. I'm going to
teach Angel Devil and then you know as I
talk think about which image you're
going to create with the AI. Okay? and
uh it'll help your teaching career.
It'll make you a better teacher.
Pictures help people stay awake and they
help people remember things. Okay? So, I
I really encourage you to use them. And
I I I my opinion is that everybody in
this class or everybody online, you can
learn to be a teacher. I believe every
person it's your
responsibility to teach this to other
people. Everybody's
different. Adam's not here. I'll tell
you something. His first class. Can I
show
you? It was about 12 years ago. It was
in Phoenix. And I I I trained him what
to say. And he got ready and he he stood
up and he went like
this. And I'm like, "Adam." He
said,
"Adam, Adam, sit down now." He's like,
"Sit down." Okay, we'll work on it. And
uh, no, he froze completely. I also
froze my first class. I didn't. My
teacher told me to sit down. Shut up.
And
uh, so you learn. Okay, you can learn.
All right, you you will learn. In my
opinion, everybody listening right now
can be a teacher and should be a
teacher. And and in the tradition of the
ancient books, you're not allowed to
take a class if you don't intend to
teach it. Okay? If you don't intend to
share it with someone, you're not
allowed to sit here in the old way. In
the old way. That's why my cat heard so
many
teachings. Sometimes nobody wants to
listen. I'm like, "Will you listen?"
She's like, "If you got that special cat
food that I really like, I'll listen."
And I'm like, "I got it." Okay. All
right. So, here we
go. I'm just going to read it fast.
Okay.
Okay. And uh the devil's talking, okay?
The bad part of your mind. And he says
you should lead people by the hand to
the nothing at
all. Teach them not to think about
anything.
make their concentration filled with
busyiness every time they meditate.
Okay. Ah the masters of meditation
inside my system. Okay. Sit down. Cross
your legs. Don't think about anything.
Oh. Okay. All right. Who's talking? I
hope you
know. Yeah. It's the devil. Okay. And
he's like, "This is my meditation
system.
And you laugh, you know, but uh I so in
my in the old days uh when I when I met
my first yoga teacher, I said, "Look, I
don't know if I can do this yoga thing."
It was Lady Ruth, right? And and David
and Sharon and I said, "I don't know if
I can do this yoga thing because I'm so
busy. I travel all the time." And they
said, "Oh, you
should we have a suggestion. When you
get to the hotel, go online, find the
nearest yoga class,
go, you know, every country you go to.
There's a wonderful story in Hong Kong
about the Chinese language
uh pregnancy class I went to. And the
lady's like mayo. I'm
like, she's like me. I said, I got the
money. She's like, me. Then I went in
there and it's all pregnant ladies and
that's the best stretch I ever got
here.
Okay. So anyway, uh but I'll tell you
something because I went to so many met
yoga classes in so many countries. Every
country I went to, I went to a yoga
class and I never met the teacher. I
heard hundreds of terrible
meditation classes. hundreds, you
know, think about
nothing, just let your flaws thrown
away, you know. I'm like, okay, you
know, and uh I then I suddenly I by
accident I realized how much bad
meditation is being taught and I was
shocked, you know, I was like very
rarely
uh anybody was teaching meditation.
Uh so this is happening 400 years ago
and this teacher this great uh writer
Bosanuki Genten he's saying he by the
way he's the one who personally stopped
the war
uh from his retreat cave okay and uh so
anyway he's saying even 400 years ago
there was a problem that people taught
meditation like just try to think about
nothing just try not to think about
anything. Okay, in this book it's the
devil. Okay,
and and that's an important thing. Okay,
when you make your
picture, okay, this is not a bad yoga
class or something, you know. By the
way, often times the yoga is good.
Oftenimes the asa is quite good. uh the
meditation before the asa is ridiculous
you know but often times the teacher is
a good yoga teacher and they teach great
asa so that's why I still go you know I
just kind
of
sug when they start the meditation I put
the earplugs in when they start the asa
I take them out you know and uh so I you
know you can go you can go and you can
learn but it's The ancient problem of
people who think that meditation is
thinking about nothing. Now
listen in a tantric sense in a diamond
way sense. Okay. The goal of diamond way
is to get the job done before you die.
Okay? And you're you don't think so. You
think, oh Gila's health's not so
good. Who's going to die first and who's
going to die last? We don't know. Okay.
Don't don't think it's it usually goes
out of order. I often sit here and
there's no one
left. You see what I'm we don't know
who's going to go first and we don't
know who's going to go last. And that's
the way it is. Okay. In in this system
of diamond way, you're trying to reach
the goal before you die. And it's a
race, you know, like there's always this
background thing called you might get in
a car accident tomorrow. You might they
might say, "Oh, you remember that nice
lady who was in Yeah, she's gone. You
know, she had a car accident." You're
like, "Oh my gosh." Then it lasts for
about three minutes. Everybody's like,
"Oh my gosh." And then you're like,
"What's for lunch anyway?" You
know, so we're all in a race. Diamond
way. One of the See, I'm sneaking you
diamond way. Every verse I'm seeking
sneaking diamond way to you. Uh it's a
race. Okay. The purpose of diamond way.
The reason for diamond way, one of the
important ideas of diamond way is get it
done and then
relax. You know, then if you don't die,
you're okay. If you do die, you're okay.
Okay. My death is different from your
death already. I know where I'm going. I
know what's happening. I know where I'm
going to be five minutes later. I got
everything
ready. The teachers are waiting for me.
Okay. And
I'm, you know, it's all set. Okay. You
got to do that. You got to take care of
that while you can. You know, you got to
take care of that. That's diamond way.
Diamond way is the big emphasis on one
life. Okay. So this person who teaches
you meditate about nothing is literally
killing you. It's not like a joke or
they don't know how to teach meditation.
They should have gone
to samadei house. Stupid guy you know
wasting my 10 minutes before class. It's
not 10 minutes before class. It's your
irreplaceable life, which is priceless.
I've sold my company to Warren Buffett.
I'm pissed at him. He went from 81
billion to 143 billion riding partly on
my company. Okay. Now he's what
90? He's 94. and his mind is, you know,
finally his mind's going, you know, and
and if he's got $143 billion, he should
be able to buy a couple hours from
somebody. Like, can he go to some poor
person and say, "Okay, $100 million a
day, I'll buy I don't care what it
costs. I'll I'll take some of your
lifetime." And they can't do it. You
know, they can't Nobody can do it. The
person who teaches you lousy
meditation is killing you. They are
stealing your priceless time. It's not a
small thing. It's a terrible thing. It's
a tragedy. It's better if they give you
diarrhea. Right,
Rob? He just had an epic
case. I'm kind of jealous because he
lost eight pounds. Okay.
Um anyway, uh it's not a joke and it's
not it's not a small thing. It's not
that you wasted 10 minutes before yoga
class. It's that no one can give it back
to you. Okay? Teaching meditation wrong
is like cutting someone's arm open or
something. You know, it's probably
kinder to cut their arm open. At least
they can put on a band-aid and keep
going, you know. Okay. So, it's very
serious. It's really serious. This is
not a It's a funny debate, but it's not
a funny debate. This guy really is
the devil because he's killing he's
killing people's hearts, not their not
their body. He's teaching them wrong
meditation. It's a terrible tragedy.
It's a It's like someone It's like
someone dying in a car accident. It's
terrible. It's a sad thing that someone
would waste their time.
Okay. All right.
[Music]
Okay, this is the devil bragging about
how fast his system works. Okay, he's
like they will attain results of
meditation that you cannot find in this
life or the next. They will achieve
Buddhahood. They can do it just goofing
off in three days with my system.
Okay? Or they could just meditate for a
month and reach Buddhahood, you know,
and they'll all go to freedom. They'll
all get liberated. Okay. Who's
talking? The devil. Okay. Listen,
diamond way is the fastest way and it
takes a long
time. Duh. Okay. All right. If someone
promised you
instant liberation, I let me tell you
something. As an old man, let me give
you some wisdom.
Okay. Someone sit down next to somebody.
This happened to me. Somebody sat down
next to somebody on a plane and they're
like, they're like, "You want to know
the secret about the stock market?" I'm
like, "What?" It's like, "You got to
invest in Nvidia. You know, it's Nvidia.
They got the they got the chips. They
got the advanced MDM chips. You know,
you unbelievable. You got to get the
money in right now, you know. you know,
and then uh the the chairman of Sony,
the founder of Sony
Corporation, what's his
name? Akil Morita. Mr. Morita. He Here's
what he
said. And it's a great book. What's the
book
[Music]
called? Made in Japan. Great book. And I
love him. And he
said, "Let me tell you something. If
someone really knows which stock's going
to go up tomorrow, you think they're
going to tell
you?" He's like, "And it the logic was
undeniable. You know, if someone
knows for sure a stock's going to go up
tomorrow, why would they tell you? you
know, they'll just put their money there
and they'll make the money. Got it? It
and he was laughing. He said, "I don't
play the stock market. I don't have any
stocks." Here's the the founder of Sony
Corporation. And he says, "I don't buy
stocks. Why? Because it's just gambling.
It's the same as horse racing or, you
know, it's exactly the same. Nobody can
tell you where it's going to go
tomorrow. You can take all the experts
in the world and they all say something
different and and if they knew they
wouldn't be an expert, they would
quietly make more money. You see what I
mean?
Duh. Why am I talking about that? This
guy's promising you impossible. Okay,
listen. I'm a tempter master. I got a
special hat. I got a ding ding ding ding
ding ding ding ding ding ding. I can say
blah blah blah ding ding ding ding ding
ding. You know, look at this thing. Look
at my robe. You know, I'm a that proves
I'm a chanting master. Ding ding ding
ding ding ding. I have sex with every
other student. You know, I I drink all,
you know, ding ding ding ding ding ding.
You know, then, you know, I could get
you there in three days. Then it's like
a stock market thing, you know. It's
like, come on. You know, you go ding
ding. I got to go to
class. Okay. Understand it. The the
doesn't it doesn't get you to Buddha.
I'm sorry. I have a hat. I never You
ever see me
in Okay.
Uh unreasonable promises that you can
get to enlightenment instantly delay
your
enlightenment. Okay. It's going to take
hard work, steady work. You're going to
have to sit on your butt in the retreat
cabin and have many bad days, right,
JB? And many hard times and
and then you get then you get to the
goal. Okay. Diamond way is not piece of
candy, but it works. Okay. All right.
Hello. Does that mean I'm supposed to
shut up,
Brian? Yeah. Okay. Okay.
I like this next verse. It's called a
who cannot tie their shoe.
in English means super stupid person.
Okay. Who's talking? Who would say such
a
thing? The devil. Okay. And he's
accusing this beautiful angel called
wisdom, understanding of the pen, miss
emptiness.
you know, she's he says, "You're just a
moron." And she's like, "Why you say
that?" She doesn't get upset, of course.
And he says, "I am capable of mighty
deeds. And you, you're just some nice
lady, you know. I've got the real
wisdom. You are like a moron." In
English, we say, "You cannot tie your
shoe." It means you're so stupid, you
can't even tie your shoe. for words
Smith. You never saw these words. This
is you knowang dialect in 1600. Very
hard to translate.
So yuk means
dumbhead
and ken means uh
weakling and jaw means that's who you
are. He's accusing her of being too
nice.
Okay. Who's talking? The devil. Yeah.
You are a who cannot tie your
shoe. You appear once and then you are
gone. He accuses her of not sticking
around. She He says, "Yeah, you're so
beautiful. You're so wise. You
understand the pen. You live by the
pen." Right? And then why why you never
home? You know where are you all
day? Who are you running around with? In
English, we say, "Who are you running
around with? Why aren't you ever come
home? You're so beautiful. You're so
compassionate. You're so wise. And
you're never
home. Why? What's he
[Music]
mean?" Yeah.
to really understand the pen is like
once a
month for like two minutes. Okay. He's
accusing her of being a bad lady, being
a bad wife. He has to live where with
her in her brain. Okay. He the devil has
to live with the angel in one person's
mind all day long and she's never home.
She's like, he's like, who's the guy?
What's his name? You know, where do you
go? What do you do? Why are you never
here? You know, got
it. It means people think about the pen
like once a week, you know, all week
long they're complaining about other
people. You know, I can't believe this
person do this. Such a such a bad
person. Hurt me so bad.
And then you're like once a month you
think, "Oh, it's coming from me. That's
what I do." Okay. She's not home very
often. Got it. You're supposed to go,
"Oh, I got
[Music]
it." So, I think it's cute. He's
accusing her of being what do you call
that? She's cheating on her husband.
Who's the
husband? Ignorance. They live together.
Okay. In our heads, they are a couple
and she's not home very often. Got it.
It's cute. Okay. You You're gonna make a
nice not X-rated
picture.
Okay. Got it. On the AI.
Okay. We got six. How
much punch minute? Okay. Uh very good.
Yeah, let's go.
Let's
Yeah. A lot of spelling
differences in this
[Music]
text. Those who hope to accumulate good
karma beyond any measure should come and
serve me at my feet. Who's
talking? You can call him twominut
Buddhahood. Two minute Buddhahood. He's
got the secret for two minute
Buddhahood. I don't understand why the
whole world isn't bowing down to my
feet. If they did my meditation
on nothing at all, they would give
Buddhahood in a couple
days. All right. Okay. If you really
want to make good karma, come serve the
devil. By the way, the devil in um in
Western, you know, they're asking you to
cheat on your taxes or something. Uh but
in in Buddhism, the devil's asking you
to think the pen comes from its own
side. That's his job. That's his only
job. If he can make you believe that the
person who insulted you yesterday was
not coming from you, then then he did
his job. Okay? He's trying to get you to
believe another person could hurt you.
Okay? And if he does that, then you
aren't his slave and you will have a
terrible life. Okay? You just keep
blaming other people your whole
life. All right? They should serve me.
You
should you should be jealous of me
because I'm so powerful and you're so
weak. Who's talking? Yeah, the devil's
bragging. Is it
true? It's not true that she's weak. She
just doesn't show up much. She's never
home. When she's home, she beats him
every
time. You know, if you think of where
the pen's coming from, you will be
patient with other people. Okay? But if
you can't
remember, you are weak. She's weak.
Okay? Got it? She's stronger, but not if
she's not at
home. If she's never visiting
home, she she doesn't get a chance to
show her power. Got it?
Okay. You got to learn this ancient GI
Michael student thing. When you're
asleep in the class, you're
like, "Okay, that's third level skill."
Second level
skill, sleep with your eyes
open. Third level skill, just stay up
and don't
go.
Okay, by now you must be so exhausted
trying to fight with me, you know. Why
don't you just don't come
home? Okay. It's such a trouble when
you're at home, you know, to doubt
whether this person's coming from me or
not. Why don't you just don't come home?
Okay. We'll just decide the person who
hurt me is coming from their side and
they're a bad person. And then we don't
have to keep trying to remember
Buddhism. Okay? It's a
hassle to be
schizophrenic. What's a
schizophrenic? He hurt me. He said
something to me. And he's coming from
me. Wait, he's coming from me. Wait, he
can't come for me. He hurt me. No. You
know, isn't it easier if you just forget
all your Buddhism? You know, someone
hurts you, you say, "What an asshole."
You know, where let me meet your mother.
Who brought you up like that? You know,
and never met such a stupid person, you
know. Wouldn't that be easier than this
Buddhist struggle inside your mind?
Maybe he's coming from me. No. No. I
mean, some people, but not
him. Okay. He's like, "Why don't you
just leave the house and stay out?"
Okay. That's his last word.
[Music]
Now the beautiful lady
reappears. Okay.
And l it means the beautiful lady is
wisdom. She comes back home. I'm here
honey. What's that? She understands a
pen and she uses it in her real life.
Some people understand the pen and never
use it in their real life and they're
complaining about other people all the
time.
Okay. And I'm complaining about
them.
Okay.
Uh, now she's talking to him. Okay, we
have one minute. Okay, hang in there.
When I was sitting in the gashi course
in a refugee camp in a 120 degree that's
Celsius with rain dripping on my head
from the roof and everybody around me
has
tuberculosis. I made a
promise. I said in the future when I'm a
teacher I'm going to make them suffer.
[Music]
Now it came
true.
Okay. I really had that thought. I mean
it's not a very good thought. Okay.
Uh ah you arrogant one. You don't
possess a single good quality. And yet
still you have a delusion that your
meditation is so cool. You're a master
meditator because you can sit there and
think about nothing. Okay. Mhm. Not only
you don't have any fine
qualities, you don't have the tools to
get those
qualities. Meaning in this case, you
don't know how to meditate. No one ever
taught you meditation. You think
thinking about nothing is
meditation. So, so you will never be a
good person because you don't have the
tools, you don't have the skill set, you
don't have the toolkit, okay? which is
meditation because you think meditation
means sitting and thinking about Okay,
cool. Kuma. Okay.
Uh, yay. What's up? Yeah. Okay.